bowers-wilkins.com 2019-07-20

# Privacy Policy | Bowers & Wilkins

**Last Updated : October 31, 2018**

We take your privacy very seriously. Please read this Privacy policy carefully as it contains important information on who we are and how and why we collect, store, use and share your personal information. It also explains your rights in relation to your personal information and how to contact us or governmental authorities in the event you have a complaint.

We collect, use and are responsible for certain personal information about you. When we do so we are subject to the California’s privacy laws and we are responsible as “controller” (data collecting and using) business of that personal information for the purposes of those laws.

You can visit our site freely without having to register or subscribe for services.

This Privacy policy contains the following sections:

 • 

| 

Key Terms  
  
---|---  
  
 • 

| 

Changes to our Privacy policy  
  
 • 

| 

What personal data do we collect about you?  
  
 • 

| 

Cookies & web analytics  
  
 • 

| 

Mobile Applications  
  
 • 

| 

How and why we use your information  
  
 • 

| 

Promotional (Direct Marketing) Communication  
  
 • 

| 

Online advertising  
  
 • 

| 

Who we will share your personal data with  
  
 • 

| 

Retention of your information  
  
 • 

| 

Where is your information held?  
  
 • 

| 

What are your rights?  
  
 • 

| 

Third party links and features  
  
 • 

| 

Child privacy  
  
 • 

| 

How we protect your information  
  
 • 

| 

Employment applicants  
  
 • 

| 

Who To Contact & Complaints  
  
 • 

| 

Do you need extra help?  
  
### Key Terms

Some key terms used in this policy are defined as follows:

**We, us, our**

| 

B&W Group Limited (doing business as B&W and Bowers & Wilkins), a limited company incorporated in England and Wales with a U.S. headquarters located at 1020 Marsh Road, Menlo Park, CA 94025.  
  
---|---  
  
**Personal information**

| 

Any information that identifies, relates to, describes, or is capable of being associated with, or could reasonably be linked, directly or indirectly, to an identified or identifiable living natural person, including but not limited to: (i) Identifiers such as a real name, alias, postal address, unique personal identifier, online identifier Internet Protocol address, email address, account name, social security number, driver’s license number, government identification card number, passport number, or other similar identifiers; and (ii) any financial information (including bank account or payment card numbers) used to pay for our products and/or services.  
  
**Products**

| 

Products and/or services relating to audio which we may supply or provide to you.  
  
### Changes to our Privacy policy

Any changes we may make to this Privacy policy in the future will be posted on this page and, where appropriate, notified to you by email. Please check back frequently to see any updates or changes to this Privacy policy. This Privacy policy was last updated on the date set forth above.

### What personal information do we collect about you?

This Privacy policy covers the information that we collect and use about you when:

 • 

| 

You access and/use the website on which this Privacy policy is displayed, our mobile applications in North America, physical products, software, or other online or mobile service that links to or otherwise presents this Privacy policy to you.  
  
---|---  
  
 • 

| 

You engage with our questionnaires, promotions, surveys or provide marketing responses to our engagement activities.  

In order to provide Products, we collect information from you and this collection of data may occur when you:

 • 

| 

Place an order for any Products  
  
---|---  
  
 • 

| 

Make an inquiry (including about any of our Products or complete a form on our websites)  
  
 • 

| 

Participate in discussion boards and/or other social media functions on our site  
  
 • 

| 

Sign up to book a demo of our Products  
  
 • 

| 

Products (including associated applications) that you use  
  
 • 

| 

Enter a competition, promotion or survey  
  
 • 

| 

Reviews that you submit about our Products  
  
 • 

| 

Register to use our site and/or subscribe to any of our Products (including Society of Sound, our newsletters and marketing communications).  
  
 • 

| 

Register any of the Products you have purchased from us  
  
 • 

| 

Correspond with us in relation to your account, our Products you have purchased (including post-sales support and warranties)  
  
 • 

| 

Report a problem with our site  
  
 • 

| 

Inquire about or submit an Employment application through our site  
  
####   
Information about you

We collect data from you directly in order to provide Products and this consists of both personally identifiable information as well as anonymized data. The type of data collected depends on the Products you are engaging with and the requirements to deliver that Product.

User Information:-

 • 

| 

Name, address, telephone number and email address (including company name/address if the Product requires this);  
  
---|---  
  
 • 

| 

Shipping and billing address, credit or debit card number, verification number, and expiration date;  
  
 • 

| 

Log-in credentials for our user accounts;  
  
 • 

| 

Warranty registration and purchase history;  
  
 • 

| 

User generated content you submit to our public forums (for example, the B&W Blog or any of our Social Media pages);  
  
 • 

| 

Information about your customer service history with us;  
  
 • 

| 

Any other information you choose to directly provide to us in connection with your use of the Services.  

In order to fulfil your shipping requests to third parties (for example, a friend or family member to whom you want to send a Product as a gift), we will use the data you provide about the third party to fulfil your shipment request. It is your responsibility to ensure that third party consents to you transferring their personal information to us.

#### Information about Products supplied by us

In order for you to download a firmware or software update/upgrade, we will require certain information regarding you and your Product. We collect this information in the following ways:

 • 

| 

Information that you provide to us - this includes Product registration information and information you provide when you subscribe for any of our services and/or use any app or download any firmware or software;  
  
---|---  
  
 • 

| 

Information we obtain from you when you use our Products or download our firmware or software - we collect information about your use of the services and/or app, or about the firmware or software you download. This information includes (but is not limited to);  
  
 · 

| 

Registration/Subscription Information – we may collect information such as your name, address, email address, contact numbers, password, product or device identifiers, preferences and payment details. We use a third party provider to store registration information and we will share your information with them solely for that purpose.  
  
---|---  
  
 · 

| 

Product Setup information - we may collect information about the Product that you are using, such as your model type, firmware version, MAC address (if applicable), BSSID, SSID and encryption mode, network type, Wi-Fi connection, unique Product identifiers, device name and mobile network information. We will associate your Product identifiers with your registration account. We use a third party provider to store registration information and app support information and we will share your information with them solely for that purpose.  
  
 · 

| 

User Experience Tracking information – we may automatically track your use of our Products in order to provide you with a better experience. We use a third party provider to carry out such tracking on our behalf and we will share your information with them solely for that purpose.  
  
 · 

| 

Online Logging /Crash Log Information – when you use our Products or download our firmware or software, we may automatically collect and store certain information, including (but not limited to): your global unique identifier; details of how you used our Products and/or downloaded our firmware or software; Product address (MAC address, if applicable); operating system and firmware/software version used; Product information such as settings, browser type and language, system activity, URL, number of Products connected, number of updates, number of resets, and crashes; recovery time and whether recovery was successful. We use this information to provide support services and for developer testing.  
  
 · 

| 

Auto Update Anonymous Profiling – We may collect anonymous profiling information, including (but not limited to) the Product name and version used, your IP address, CPU speed, operating system, system model, installed RAM, language, network interface card type and description, use of WLAN, use of Touch Input, installation of Net Runtime.  
  
 · 

| 

Location Information – we may collect information about your country location.  
  
 · 

| 

Local Storage – we may collect and store information (including personal information) locally on your product or device.  
  
Please let us know if you would like any further details relating to third party processing of your personal data in relation to the above.

#### Information we collect through automated technologies

We use automated technologies to gather data when you use our Products. This data is processed by both us and third party service providers working on our behalf. The data is collected by both us and our services providers using technologies including (but not limited to) cookies, web analytics and beacons. See also " _Cookies & web analytics_" below.

#### Websites

We automatically collect the following information about visitors to our site:

 • 

| 

Date/time of visit  
  
---|---  
  
 • 

| 

Pages visited, including the last page visited before the visitor exits the site  
  
 • 

| 

Time spent on each page of the site  
  
 • 

| 

Referring site details - the URL through which the user came to the site and the search terms used by the visitor to find the site  
  
 • 

| 

Type of web browser used by the visitor  
  
 • 

| 

The visitor's operating system  
  
 • 

| 

The visitor's computer's Flash version, JavaScript support, screen resolution and screen color processing ability  
  
 • 

| 

The visitor's network location and IP address  
  
 • 

| 

The visitor's browser's default language  
  
 • 

| 

What the visitor downloaded  
  
#### **Information we collect from third parties**

We may also collect the following information provided by third parties:-

 • 

| 

Publicly available information about you or your business (including through electronic data sources)  
  
---|---  
  
 • 

| 

Personal data about you from third parties (e.g. our business partners, dealer networks, sub-contractors in technical, payment, fulfilment and delivery services, advertising networks, analytics providers, and search information providers) to enable us to customize or personalize Products for you.  
  
####   
Information we collect from social media platforms

If you like or follow posts on social media or post to our feeds (including Twitter and Facebook, among others) then we may collect information about your account such as name, username, email address and content relevant to our Products.

### Cookies & web analytics

As part of the automated collection of data, we and our third party service providers may use server logs, cookies, web beacons, Google Analytics and other similar technologies.

For more detail on our Cookies policy please see our policy  _here_.

To opt out of being tracked by Google Analytics across all websites visit  _[http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout.](http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout)_

### Mobile Applications

When you use one of our mobile applications or software, we automatically receive certain information about the mobile phone, table, or computer using the software, including (but not limited to):

 • 

| 

IP addresses of the device running the software and any products that it is working with  
  
---|---  
  
 • 

| 

Information on the network the device and products are working together on (including SSID and network encryption method)  
  
 • 

| 

User settings and configurations of the app and devices  
  
 • 

| 

Time and date of use, including time spent in different parts of the app  
  
 • 

| 

Details on how you use our products and services offered in apps, firmware and software  

We use this information to provide support services and for developer testing and this includes sharing this information with third party developers. We store some information on third party services and therefore they hold and pass this information to us. Please contact us if you wish to obtain further details.

### How and why we use your information

The table below explains what we use (process) your personal information for and our reasons for doing so:

**What we use your personal information for**

| 

**Our reasons**  
  
---|---  
  
To provide Products and/or related information to you

| 

For the performance of our contract with you or to take steps at your request before entering into a contract 

To comply with our legal and regulatory obligations  
  
To prevent and detect fraud against you or us

| 

For our legitimate interests or those of a third party, that is, to minimize fraud that could be damaging for us and for you  
  
Conducting checks to identify you and verify your identity

Screening for financial and other sanctions or embargoes

Other processing necessary to comply with professional, legal and regulatory obligations that apply to our business

| 

To comply with our legal and regulatory obligations  
  
Gathering and providing information required by or relating to inquiries or investigations by governmental bodies

| 

To comply with our legal and regulatory obligations  
  
Operational reasons, such as improving efficiency, training and quality control

| 

For our legitimate interests or those of a third party, that is, to be as efficient as we can so we can deliver the best service for you at the best price  
  
Statistical analysis to help us manage our site and/or business: for example, in relation to customer base, Product range or other efficiency measures

| 

For our legitimate interests or those of a third party: that is, to be as efficient as we can so we can deliver the best service for you at the best price  
  
Preventing unauthorized access and modifications to our site and/or systems

| 

For our legitimate interests or those of a third party- that is, to prevent and detect criminal activity that could be damaging for us and for you

To comply with our legal and regulatory obligations  
  
Updating and enhancing customer records

| 

For the performance of our contract with you or to take steps at your request before entering into a contract

To comply with our legal and regulatory obligations

For our legitimate interests or those of a third party – for example, making sure that we can keep in touch with our customers about existing orders and new products  
  
Marketing our Products and, where agreed, those products of selected third parties to:

—existing and former customers;

—third parties who have previously expressed an interest in our Products;

—third parties with whom we have had no previous dealings.

| 

For our legitimate interests or those of a third party, for example, to promote our business to existing and former customers  
  
Credit reference checks via external credit reference agencies

| 

For our legitimate interests or those of a third party – that is, to ensure our customers are likely to be able to pay for our products and services  
  
Administering, managing and maintaining your accounts and/or subscriptions with us

| 

For the performance of our contract with you or to take steps at your request before entering into a contract.

For our legitimate interests or those of a third party- that is, to be as efficient as we can so we can deliver the best service for you at the best price  
  
Corresponding with you in relation to your account, our Products you have purchased (including post-sales support and warranties)

| 

For the performance of our contract with you or to take steps at your request before entering into a contract

For our legitimate interests or those of a third party - that is, to be as efficient as we can so we can deliver the best service for you at the best price  
  
Notifying you about changes to our Products and/or our site

| 

For the performance of our contract with you or to take steps at your request before entering into a contract

For our legitimate interests or those of a third party, that is, to be as efficient as we can so we can deliver the best service for you at the best price  
  
Customizing our Products to provide more personalized content

| 

For our legitimate interests or those of a third party, that is, to be as efficient as we can so we can deliver the best service for you at the best price  
  
Measuring or understanding the effectiveness of advertising we serve to you and others, and to deliver relevant advertising to you

| 

For our legitimate interests or those of a third party - that is, to be as efficient as we can so we can deliver the best service for you at the best price  

Data may be aggregated into anonymized data sets, which means the data can no longer be linked to any individuals. This analysis may be used for such purposes (but not limited to) as product research, marketing and service optimization and this anonymized data may also be shared with third parties such as advertising and market research partners.

### Promotional Direct Marketing Communication

We may use your personal information to send you updates (by email, text message, telephone or post) about our Products, including exclusive offers, promotions or new Products.

We will always treat your personal information with the utmost respect and never sell it to other organizations outside our group of companies for marketing purposes.

You have the right to opt out of receiving promotional communications at any time by:

We may ask you to confirm or update your marketing preferences if you ask us to provide further Products in the future, or if there are changes in the law, regulation, or the structure of our business.

Note, however, that after you opt out of promotional communications, we will still send you emails relating to the support, administration, and security of our Products and Services.

### Online advertising

We may integrate third party advertising platform technologies and services with the data we collect to serve relevant advertising content on the Services and other applications you use. This process may use any of the data collected as set out in this Privacy policy to deliver the targeted advertising.

These third party partners may place cookies and other auto tracking technologies as part of their service. There may be occasions when we supply our customer information (such as email addresses) to service providers, who may combine the data provided by us with cookies and other tracking data in an anonymized way (e.g. Hashed matching) to enhance their service provision.

We do not have access to or control of automated tracking processes used by third party service providers. To understand options to opt out of these third party service please refer to the Cookies and Web Analytics section of this Privacy policy as well as online resources for opt out such as [Network Advertising Initiative](https://www.networkadvertising.org/), [Digital Advertising Alliance](http://digitaladvertisingalliance.org/), or [Your Online Choices](http://www.youronlinechoices.com/uk/).

#### Do Not Track California Residents’ Notice:

“Do not track” (DNT) is a web browser setting that requests that a web application disable its tracking of an individual user. When you choose to turn on the DNT setting in your browser, your browser sends a special signal to websites, analytics companies, ad networks, plug in providers, and other web services you encounter while browsing to stop tracking your activity. For details on setting DNT on your browser of choice, please refer to the help pages or settings for your particular browsers.

California law requires online service providers to disclose in their privacy policies how they respond to “do not track” settings that users can set in their browser software. Currently, there is no standard governing how a website operator should respond when receiving a “do not track” signal. Accordingly, we do not currently take action in response to a “do not track” browser setting. We will revise this policy if an industry standard regarding such settings emerges.

### Who we will share your personal data with

We routinely share personal information with:

 • 

| 

companies within our group;  
  
---|---  
  
 • 

| 

third parties we use to help deliver our Products to you – for example, payment service providers/gateways, warehouses and delivery companies;  
  
 • 

| 

other third parties we use to help us run our business – for example, marketing agencies or website hosts, marketing communication platforms, analytics and reporting systems;  
  
 • 

| 

third parties which operate review websites which provide you with an opportunity to share feedback on our Products with others.  

We only allow our service providers to handle your personal information if we are satisfied they take appropriate measures to protect your personal information. We also impose contractual obligations on service providers relating to ensure they can only use your personal information to provide services to us and to you.

We may disclose and exchange personal information with law enforcement agencies and regulatory bodies to comply with our legal and regulatory obligations.  We may also disclose personal information to respond to a subpoena, court order, search warrant, administrative or judicial process.  Also, we may disclose your personal information to preserve the security of our website or social media accounts, resolve disputes, or to assess any possible wrongdoing.

We may also need to share some personal information with other parties, such as potential buyers of some or all of our business, during bankruptcy or insolvency proceedings, or in negotiations of such transactions. The recipient of the information will be bound by confidentiality obligations and we will seek to require the buyer to maintain the limitations and restrictions of this Privacy policy.

#### Service Providers

We may share your personal data with selected third parties in the following instances

 • 

| 

business partners, dealer networks, suppliers and sub-contractors for the performance of a contract we enter into with them in connection with your account, our products, services (including post-sales support and warranties) and/or our site (including our hosting providers);  
  
---|---  
  
 • 

| 

to maintain, develop and/or host your account and/or our site;  
  
 • 

| 

with analytics and search engine providers that assist us in the improvement and optimization of our Products and our site;  
  
 • 

| 

where we carry out marketing, advertising or surveys to gain feedback and improve our Products and/or our site.  
  
####   
**Public Forums**

We provide public forums in which it is possible for you to upload content. We reserve the right to use all user-generated content in connection with our Products: for example, comments and images may be used on our site as a testimonial.

### Where is your information held?

Information may be held at our offices and those of our group companies, third party agencies, service providers, representatives and agents as described above (see above: " _Who we will share your personal data with_").

### What are your rights?

Under a California law to become effective in 2020, the California Consumer Privacy Act, you will have the following rights:

Access

| 

The right to be provided with a copy of your personal information and an accounting of the disclosures of your personal information (the right of access)  
  
---|---  
  
To be forgotten

| 

The right to require us to delete your personal information—in certain situations  
  
Data portability

| 

The right to receive the personal information you provided to us, in a structured, commonly used and machine-readable format and/or transmit that data to a third party—in certain situations  
  
To object

| 

The right to object at any time to your personal information being sold for direct marketing (including profiling).  

For further information on each of those rights, including the circumstances in which they apply, please contact us.

If you would like to exercise any of those rights, please:

 • 

| 

email or write to our Data Protection Officer—see below: " _Our contact information_"; and  
  
---|---  
  
 • 

| 

let us have enough information to identify you – for example, your full name, address and customer or invoice/order number;  
  
 • 

| 

let us have proof of your identity and address (a copy of your driving license or passport and a recent utility or credit card bill); and  
  
 • 

| 

let us know what right you want to exercise and the information to which your request relates.  
  
### Third party links and features

Our site may, from time to time, contain links to and from the websites of third parties. If you follow a link to any of these websites, please note that these websites have their own privacy policies and that we do not accept any responsibility or liability for these policies. Please check these policies before you submit any personal data to these websites.

### Child privacy

We provide our Products to persons aged 18 and over. We expect those under 18 years to have a parent or guardian obtain any Products on behalf of a minor. If we are made aware that we have data for people aged under 18 without such consent then we will make all responsible efforts to delete the data in line with our legal obligations.

### How we protect your information

We have appropriate security measures to prevent personal information from being accidentally lost, or used or accessed unlawfully. We limit access to your personal information to those who have a genuine business need to access it. Those processing your information will do so only in an authorized manner and are subject to a duty of confidentiality.

We also have procedures in place to deal with any suspected data security breach. We will notify you and any applicable regulator of a suspected data security breach where we are legally required to do so.

All information you provide to us is stored on our secure servers. Any payment transactions are transmitted over a secure encrypted connection (Transport Layer Security-TLS) and comply with Payment Card Industry Data Security Standards (PCI DSS). Where we have given you (or where you have chosen) a password which enables you to access certain parts of our site, you are responsible for keeping this password confidential. We ask you not to share a password with anyone.

The transmission of information via the internet is not completely secure. Although we will do our best to protect your personal data, we cannot guarantee the security of your personal data transmitted to our site; any transmission is at your own risk. Once we have received your personal data, we will use strict procedures and security features to try to prevent unauthorized access.

### Employment applications

We may, from time to time, offer online information about job vacancies and employment opportunities. The service may be provided by third party service providers (such as but not limited to BambooHR) working on our behalf. As such they may also make use of cookies and other means of collecting information, but when done such information is strictly used only for analytics purposes and to facilitate the processing of the application.

Information that we collect in connection with employment applications is handled consistent with this Privacy policy and any legal obligations to which we are subject. We reserve the right to share your information only for employment purposes, such as evaluating your eligibility or communicating with you about your registered interest.

Any third party partners are required by us to comply with the restrictions and limitations in this Privacy policy and applicable law.

### Our contact information

If you wish to contact us or have any questions about or complaints in relation to this Privacy policy, please email us at [info@bowerswilkins.com](mailto:info@bowerswilkins.com) or _click here_ for additional global B&W contact information.

If you have any questions regarding this Privacy policy, believe we have breached a privacy law or wish to exercise your rights (see “What are Your Rights?”), please contact our data protection officer as follows:

 • 

| 

By email: [gdpr@bowerswilkins.com](mailto:gdpr@bowerswilkins.com); or  
  
---|---  
  
 • 

| 

By postal mail: Data Protection Officer, B&W Group Limited, 1020 Marsh Road, Menlo Park, CA 94025  
  
Please contact us at the above information if you wish to exercise one of your rights; if you wish to copy, update, or change personal information we have on file for you; or if you wish to opt out of any marketing communications.  

California law also gives you right to lodge a complaint with the California Attorney General’s office. The Attorney General’s office who may be contacted at <https://oag.ca.gov/contact/consumer-complaint-against-business-or-company> or telephone: 916) 210-6276.

Do you need extra help?

If you would like this notice in another format or another language, please contact us (see " _Our contact information_" above).
